Guide to the Louis Napoleon Parker Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Louis Napoleon Parker Papers
1869-1943
Parker, Louis Napoleon, 1852-1944.
12.5 linear feet ( 25 document boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript library, New York, NY.
4079198
This collection contains the papers of Louis Napoleon Parker, an English playwright, translator, and historical pageant producer active in the theater from the 1890s until the early 1940s. The collection includes holograph manuscripts, typescripts, and printed editions of Parker’s plays, prose and poetry; theater programs and newspaper reviews; a small selection of sheet music; correspondence; personal documents, including datebook-style diaries; photographs; several books belonging to Parker; and his portrait in chalk by Cyril Roberts.
Biographical Note
Louis Napoleon Parker (1852-1944) was a popular and successful mainstream English playwright, producer of historical pageants, and musician, as well as a prolific translator of drama in French and Italian. A contemporary of George Bernard Shaw, Henry Arthur Jones, Arthur Wing Pinero and J.M. Barrie, Parker saw his plays performed by some of the finest actors of his day, including Sir Herbert Beerbohm Tree, Mrs. Patrick Campbell, and E.S. Willard. His historical pageants were attended by English people of all socioeconomic backgrounds, from the villagers of Warwick to the nobility.
Parker, born at Luc-sur-Mer in Calvados, France to an Englishwoman, Elizabeth Moray, and an American, Charles Albert Parker, spent his childhood in several European countries; his first language was Italian, and he spoke, read and wrote in at least French and German as well. At seventeen, his parents sent Parker to the Royal Academy of Music, then under the direction of William Sterndale Bennett. The young man began to distinguish himself as a singer, pianist and organist, and in 1873 he was sent by Bennett to serve at the Sherborne School in Dorset, first as locum tenens to the piano master and then as director of music, a position Parker held until 1892. Parker greatly increased both the musical achievement and the profile of the school, while composing his own music, including three cantatas and a set of school songs for Sherborne. During his time in Sherborne, Parker became an early member of the original Wagner Society, and later served as president of the organization that succeeded it.
In 1878 Parker was married to Georgiana Bessie Calder (c.1853-1919), the daughter of a Sherborne merchant; they had two daughters, Elsa (whom Parker nicknamed “Toby”) and Dorothy (whom he called “Tommy”). Dorothy became an actress, starring in the very successful American production of her father's comedy Pomander Walk.
Parker, who began to experience deafness in the early 1890s, left both Sherborne and his music and teaching careers in 1892, though he remained a member of the Royal Academy of Music until the end of his long life.
After leaving Sherborne, Parker turned to London and to the theater. He already had some experience as a playwright and also as a translator of European drama; indeed, Parker's 1889 edition of Henrik Ibsen's Rosmersholm, along with William Archer's series of translations, had helped to introduce Ibsen to the English-speaking world. Though Parker's own plays display nothing like Ibsen's versions of realism, the translation shows the extent to which Parker understood contemporary developments in the theater. Parker's own theatrical career began slowly, but collaborations with Murray Carson (who occasionally used the pseudonym Thornton Clark), including Gudgeons (1893) and Rosemary, That's for Remembrance (1896) brought him a measure of popularity in both England and the United States. Especially successful were Parker's plays The Cardinal (1903), Disraeli (1911), Drake (1912), Joseph and his Brethren (1913), and (with W. W. Jacobs) Beauty and the Barge (1904), and "Pomander Walk" (1910). Parker also produced a number of dramatic adaptations of novels and stories, including David Copperfield (The Highway of Life), Cyrano de Bergerac, and Jacobs's story The Monkey's Paw. His translations include plays by Louis Tiercelin, Ludwig Fulda and Edmond Rostand. Many of Parker's plays were successfully staged at His Majesty's Theatre by Sir Herbert Beerbohm Tree, but they often traveled to America, as the programs and reviews in this collection from Boston and New York show. The Cardinal received several productions in Italy, as well, and Beauty and the Barge traveled to Germany (as Das Herz auf der Hand).
In 1905, Parker created his first historical pageant, at his former home town of Sherborne. At Sherborne, nine hundred participants produced seven performances so successfully that Parker was quickly besieged by requests from other towns. Over the next five years, he created large-scale pageants for Warwick, Bury St. Edmunds, Colchester, York, and Dover. Parker's pageants, usually conducted outdoors and involving a high degree of spectacle, celebrated official English history and values. Indeed, Parker was himself intensely pro-English, and he became a British subject in 1914, just before World War I began.
Parker spent many of his later years in Devon. He continued writing, producing the screenplay Nelson for the “talkies” and occasional verse. His play Disraeli, starring George Arliss, was produced as a film in 1936. Parker died at Bishopsteignton, in Devon, on 21 September 1944.
Many of Parker's plays were not published, and he did not retain manuscripts after typed copies were made; for this reason, the typescripts and manuscripts included in this collection are often the only known copies of the works. Parker's daughters, and then his grandson, Anthony Parker Tull, used these volumes when administering the literary estate.
Scope and Content
The Papers include an apparently complete collection of Parker's plays, many of which remain unpublished; most are typescripts bound especially for Parker, though some of the plays are in manuscript, and a very few are unbound. A number of these play scripts are annotated in Parker's hand, and some are bound with programs, newspaper clippings, and, in a few instances, with production photographs. Printed copies of several of Parker's plays are also included. The Papers also contain volumes of Parker's light verse and prose; his correspondence, datebook-style diaries and other personal documents; programs for productions of nearly all of Parker's plays; and newspaper clippings (generally contemporary reviews). The collection is completed by two small series: books owned by Parker, mostly presentation copies, and photographs. The Papers also include a portrait of Parker, in chalk, by Cyril Roberts.
Arrangement
The Papers are arranged by genre and by medium, alphabetically:
Series I: Correspondence, 1887-1943
Series II: Personal Material, 1879-1942
Sub-series I.1: Diaries, 1897-1941
Sub-series I.2: Other Personal Material, 1879-1942
Series III: Writings, 1869-1941
Series IV: Other Professional Work, 1907-1937
Sub-series IV.1: Sheet Music, undated
Sub-series IV.2: Theater-related Material, undated-1918
Series V: Programs, Clippings and Posters, 1888-1939
Series VI: Photographs, 1876-1933
Series VII: Books, 1881-1937
Subjects
Longman (Firm); Allotte de la Fuÿe, Marguerite, b. 1874.; Archer, William, 1856-1924.; Barrie, J. M. (James Matthew), 1860-1937.; Bonaparte, François-Charles-Joseph, Herzog von Reichstadt, 1811-1832.; Carson, Murray.; Child, Harold Hannyngton, 1869-1945.; Disraeli, Bejamin, Earl of Beaconsfield, 1804-1881.; Fleming, George, 1858-1938.; Graves, Alfred Perceval, 1846-1931.; Irving, Henry, Sir, 1838-1905.; Jacobs, W. W. (William Wymark), 1863-1943.; Jones, Henry Arthur, 1851-1929.; Joseph--(Son of Jacob)--In literature.; Langtry, Lillie, 1853-1929.; Kipling, Rudyard, 1865-1936.; Mansfield, Richard, 1857-1907.; Maugham, W. Somerset (William Somerset), 1874-1965.; Medici, House of--Drama.; Pain, Barry, 1864-1928.; Parker, Louis Napoleon, 1852-1944.; Scott, Clement, 1841-1904.; Sinclair, May.; Tree, Herbert Beerbohm, Sir, 1853-1917.; Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883.; Ward, Humphry, Mrs., 1851-1920.; Wells, H. G. (Herbert George), 1866-1946.; United States--Description and travel.; Actors.; Dramatists.; Theatrical producers and directors.; Drama.; Pageants--England--Bury St. Edmunds.; Pageants--England.; Pageants--England--Colchester.; Pageants--England--Dover.; Pageants--England--Sherborne.; Pageants--England--Warwick.; Pageants--England--York.; Theater--United States.; Theater--England.; World War, 1914-1918--Drama.; World War, 1914-1918--Poetry.; Diaries.; Playbills.; Scripts.; Dramatists, English.; Composers.; Poets, English.; Translators.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library Reading Room. Please consult the Rare Book and Manuscript Library for further information.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1975 M-75 Lohf, Kenneth A. Gift
03/23/93 15 boxes added containing mostly typescripts of his plays Edwards, Christopher Purchase
Gift of Kenneth A. Lohf, 1975.
Purchase, 1993.
Finding aid in repository; folder level control.
- Series I: Correspondence, 1887-1943.
  This series consists of letters, telegrams and postcards written to and from Parker throughout his long professional life. The series includes correspondence from a number of prominent figures in the late nineteenth and early twentieth century literary and theatrical spheres, including William Archer, Hermann Bahr, J.M. Barrie, Harold Child, John Drew, John Drinkwater, Edouard Dujardin, Charles Frohman, Harry Furniss, Constance Fletcher (pseudonym George Fleming), Marguerite Allotte de le Fuÿe, Alfred Percival Graves, Alexander Hevesi, Laurence Irving, William Wymark Jacobs, Henry Arthur Jones, Rudyard Kipling (half a page of a letter survives), Edward Knoblock, the publishers John Lane and R.G. Longman, Marie Lohr, Lillie Langtry, Percy Macquoid, Richard Mansfield, A.E.W. Mason, Cyril Maude, W.S. Maugham, Justin H. McCarthy, William Millington, Frédéric Mistral, Ernest Newman, Barry Pain, Gilbert Parker, Edward Linley Sambourne, Clement Scott, Arthur Shirley, George R. Sims, May Sinclair, Douglas Sladen, Henry de Vere Stacpoole, Fred Terry, Julia Nielsen Terry, Phyllis Terry, Louis Tiercelin, Maud Tree, Viola Tree, Sir Herbert Beerbohm Tree, Frederick Herbert Trench, Mary A. (Mrs. Humphry) Ward, Herbert Waring, Arthur Waugh, H.G. Wells, and E.S. Willard.
  - A (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - B (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bright, R. Golding (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - C (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - D (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - E (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - F (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Fletcher, Constance (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - de la Fuÿe, Marguerite Allotte (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - G (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Graves, Alfred Percival (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - H (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Harrison, Mary B. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - I (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - J (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Jacobs, William Wymark (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Jones, Henry Arthur (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - K (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - L (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Lohr, Marie (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Longman, Robert Guy (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - M (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Mackenzie, Alexander, Sir (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - N (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - O (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - P (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Parker, Louis Napoleon (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - R (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - S (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - T (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Tiercelin, Louis (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Tree, Herbert Beerbohm, Sir (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - U (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - V (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - W (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Willard, Edward Smith (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - XYZ (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Anonymous (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Postcards (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Series II: Personal Material, 1879-1942.
  This series contains Parker’s diaries and personal documents such as passports and financial records.
  - Subseries II.1: Diaries, 1897-1941
    These date-book-style diaries include little information about Parker’s personal life; however, they give very detailed information about which projects Parker was working on during the time periods the entries cover.
    - Every Hour Diary, 1897 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Every Hour Diary, 1898 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Every Hour Diary, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Every Hour Diary, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Every Hour Diary, 1906 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Every Hour Diary, 1908 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Every Hour Diary, 1908 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Daily Diary, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Every Hour Diary, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Every Hour Diary, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Every Hour Diary, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Subseries II.2: Other Personal Material, 1879-1942
    Two of Parker’s passports are included in this sub-series, as well as signed guest books, menus for dinners given in Parker’s honor; and ephemera such as tickets and wedding and funeral programs. Included here is a portrait of Parker, in chalk (25” by 19”), by Cyril Roberts, dated 1920, located in map case 14-16-04.
    - Passports (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - "Louis N. Parker Dinner and Presentation, Hyde Park Hotel, March 9, 1919," (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - "York Historic Pageant, 1909. Presentation to Louis N. Parker, Esq. (List of Subscribers)" (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Menus, 1910-1919 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - General Printed Material, undated, 1896-1911, 1922, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Portrait of Parker, in chalk, by Cyril Roberts (25"x19"), 1920. (Box 14-16-04)
- Series III: Writings, 1869-1941.
  This series consists of an apparently complete collection of Parker’s plays, many of which remain unpublished; most are typescripts bound especially for Parker in half-morocco, with the spine of each volume lettered in gilt, though some of the plays are in manuscript, and a very few are unbound. A number of these play scripts are annotated in Parker’s hand, and some are bound with programs, newspaper clippings, and, in a few instances, with production photographs. Printed copies of several of Parker’s plays are also included; those intended for private circulation are shelved with the Papers, while editions are shelved in Rare Books. The series also contains a large holograph volume of Parker’s light verse, entitled Trifles Light as Air, and a hand-illustrated book of poetry and prose, called Rhymes by L.N.P. A bibliography of the published editions of Parker’s writings, which have been integrated into the Rare Books Library, is included at the beginning of this series.
  - The Abyss. A Play in Three Acts and an Epilogue by Parker, 1931 January 15 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - All Hallows Eve. A Play in Four Acts by Parker, 1894 November-December (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Angelo (alternate title The Amazing Story of Maestro Angelo ). A Play in a Prologue and Three Acts, [1923] (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - The Aristocrat. A Play in Three Acts by Parker, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Baldur. A Lyrical drama in four acts by Una Ashworth Taylor. Set to music by Parker, 1883 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Beauty and the Beast. A Play by François Porché. Paraphrased by Parker, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The Beggar Queen. A Play in Three Acts, by Parker, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - The Brotherhood of the Rose. A Play in Three Acts by Rudolph Lothar, 1905 August 28 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - The Cardinal. A Play in Four Acts by Parker, [1903] (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Chamillac. A Comedy in Four Acts by Octave Feuillet Adapted by Parker, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Chanticleer. A Play in Four Acts by Edmond Rostand Paraphrased by Parker, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Chanticleer. A Play in Four Acts by Edmond Rostand Paraphrased by Parker, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - "Chris" A Realistic Play in Three Acts by Parker, 1888 November 9 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Chris. A New and Original Play in Three Acts, Parker, [1892] (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Comrades by Parker I, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Comrades by Parker. VII-End, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Danton. A Play in Five Acts. Acts I and II by Parker and Hilaire Belloc, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - David. A Play in Four Acts; The BlueBoar. A Farce in 3 Acts by Parker and Thornton Clark, undated, [1894] (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - David Garrick. A new Version of an Old Play by Parker, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - The Deliverer. A Biblical Play in Five Acts by Parker, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Disraeli. A play in four Acts by Parker, 1916 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - The Diversions of an Empress. A Drama in a Prologue, Four Acts and an Epilogue, by Max Dauthendey. Paraphrased by Parker, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Drake. A Pageant-Play in Three Acts and an Epilogue by Parker, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Drake. Epilogue, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - The Duel. A Play in Three Acts by Henri Lavedan. Translated by Parker, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Everybody's Secret. A Comedy in Three Acts, [1905] (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - "For the League of Mercy," 1922 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Gudeons (alternate title The Compleat Angler ). An Original Comedy in Three Acts by Thornton Clark and Parker; Peronella. A Play in One Act by Thornton Clark and Parker, undated, 1893 February 13. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - The Hand of the Latch, undated. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - The Happy Life. A Comedy in Four Acts. By Parker, 1897-1902. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Harlequin. A Play in Two Dreams and Three Acts by Maurice Magre. Freely Translated by Parker. Music by André Gailhard, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - "Harlequin". A Comedy in Four Acts by Rudolph Lothar, [1906] (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - The Heel of Achilles. A Play in Five Acts by Parker and Boyle Lawrence, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - The Highway of Life Being the Personal History of David Copperfield by Charles Dickens. Made into a Play in Four Acts by Parker, [1914] (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - The House. A Play in Three Acts by Georges Mitchell Adapted by Parker, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Illusions. A Play in Three Acts by Henri Bernstein Adapted by Parker, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - The Jest. A Play in Four Acts. By Parker and Murray Carson, [1898] (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - John Bletchley's Wife. A Play in Four Acts by Parker, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - King Henry (alternate title Bluff King Hal ). A Play in Three Acts by Parker, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - The Labourer. A play in Four Acts by Parker and Addison Bright, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - The Lady of Coventry. A Play in Four Acts by Parker, [1911] (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - The Lady of the Manor (La Chatelaine). A Comedy in Four Acts by Alfred Capus. Freely translated by Parker, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - The Lady of the Skymy Hill. Undated. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Lancelot (Sir Lancelot of the Lake). A Tragedy in Five Acts By Parker, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - The Lily of France. A Play in Five Acts By Parker (First Version), undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - The Lord of Death. A Play in a Prologue and Three Acts by Marguerite Allotte de la Fuÿe. Translated by Parker, [1909] (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Lorna Doone. A Romance of Exmoor. By R.D. Blackmore. Arranged for the Stage by Parker, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - The Lost Duchess. A Comedy in Three Acts by Parker, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Lourdes. A Play in Three Acts by Parker, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Love in Idleness, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - The Love Knot. An Original Play in Four Acts. By Parker, 1888 March 16 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Magda (Heimat). A Play in Four Acts by Hermann Sudermann, translated by Parker, [1900] (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - La Main de Singe. Conte Dramatique en Trois Tableaux. Parker and W.W. Jacobs. Adaptation de Robert Nunès, 1905 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Marika. A Comedy in Three Acts by István Zágon. Translated by Parker, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Marion. A Play in Three Acts Founded on Theodore Winthrop's Novel "Cecil Dreeme" by Louis Calvert and Parker, 1876? (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Mavourneen. The Irish Maid. A Comedy in Four Acts by Parker, 1914 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Mavourneen. A Comedy in Three Acts by Parker, [1915] (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - The Mayflower. A Play in Three Acts by Parker, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - "A Minuet," undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - The Moon Looks On. A Comedy in Three Acts by Nino Berrini. Translated by Parker, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Mr. George. A Comedy in Four Acts by Parker, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - My Son's Wife (alternate title My Daughter-In-Law ). A Comedy in Three Acts by Fabrice Carré and Paul Bilhaud., undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Nelson. A Screen-play by Parker, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Nelson. Part II, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - The Nut Brown Maid. Synopsis of Plot, 1902 December 18. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - One Act Plays, I. Includes The Spell-Bound Garden. A Masque by Parker and Murray Carson; On the Road by James Houston; The Sacramant of Judas. A Play in One Act by Louis Tiercelin. Translated by Parker; The Creole. A Play in One Act by Parker; "Jemmy"." A Play in One Act by Parker; "The Monkey's Paw A Story in Three Scenes by W.W. Jacobs. Dramatised by Parker; Squire Coe of West Row; The Sheriff and the Woman. A Play in One Act by Parker, 1889-1906 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - One Act Plays, II. Includes "The Sequel" A Play in One Act by Parker; Reply Paid; A Private Rehersal; The Agony Column, A Duologue by Parker; A Literal Interpretation; Mrs. Mainwaring Regrets (alternate title, Mrs. Mainwaring Makes Up Her Mind ). A Monologue by Parker; The Tame Cat. A Commedia in One Act by Parker; The Ordeal of Shirley Malpas, A Play in One Act by Parker, undated, 1893-1895 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - One Act Plays, III. Includes A North Pole. A Play in One Act by Louis Tiercelin. Translated by Parker; The Masque of War and Peace by Parker; On The Road. By James Houston; Mpnsieur D'Artagnan. A Play in One Act by Parker, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Once Upon A Time (alternate title The King's New Clothes ). A Comedy in Four Acts by Ludwig Fulda. Freely done into English by Parker. 24 December 1893 December 24 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - The Pageant of Freedom. By Parker, 1918 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - The Paper Chase, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - The Pilgrim of Love. A Play in Four Acts by Edmond Rostand. Done into English by Parker, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - The Pilgrim of Love. A Play in Three Acts by Parker, April 1901 April 21 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - The Pirate. A Farce in Three Acts by Parker, 1917 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - A Play (alternate title The Great Day ). In Five Acts, 1919 July (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Playing With Fire. A Comedy in Three Acts by Roberto Bracco, Translated by Parker, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Pomander Walk. A Comedy in Three Acts by Parker, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - "A Prologue to be Spoken by Dorothy Parker on the Occasion of the Performance by Children of Pomander Walk for the Benefit of Saint Mary's Hospital for Children New York," undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Queen O' the Dials, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Queen Victoria. A Play in Five Acts by Parker, [1923] (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Queen Victoria. By Parker, [1923] (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Queen Victoria. A Play in Five Acts by Parker, [1923] (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Queen Victoria. A Play in Five Acts by Parker, [1923] (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - "Queen Victoria." Speech and related notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Ragged Robin. A Play in Four Acts. Freely Adapted from Jean Richepin's Le Chemineau by Parker, 1898 January 12 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Rhymes By L.N.P.., Vol. I. Whereunto is added moreover: "Prose by L.N.P.", 1869 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Richard Lion-Heart. A Romance in Three Acts and an Interlude by Parker, 1917 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - The Right Hand of the Prince. A Play in Three Acts by Parker, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)